<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RealCodez</title>
    <description>Where real world development meets real world failure and frustration for your entertainucation.
</description>
    <link>http://realcodez.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://realcodez.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 20:47:15 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 20:47:15 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>RealCodez Pilot</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings, salutations, holas, and welcome to the RealCodez screencasts
thingamabob. At least, the soft open version. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was listening to one of the first &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greaterthancode.com/&quot;&gt;Greater Than Code&lt;/a&gt; 
podcasts with 
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greaterthancode.com/podcast/episode-002-avdi-grimm/&quot;&gt;Avdi Grimm&lt;/a&gt;
 and during their discussion, Avdi shared some of the behind-the-scenes
 production work that goes into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rubytapas.com/&quot;&gt;RubyTapas&lt;/a&gt; that
 most are probably unaware of, and while that’s necessary to produce a clean product,
 it has the one downside of “hiding the mess” from viewers. The panel went
 on to discuss the various Impostor Syndrome implications this presents. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of software instruction has this same challenge. In order to 
 clearly teach a specific technique, all of the usual real world clutter needs
 to be removed. But there are some interesting counter-examples. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geoffrey Grosenbach’s PeepCode videos (now at PluralSight) include Play-by-Play episodes
showing real life peoples solving real life problems, which I was a big fan of (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pluralsight.com/courses/play-by-play-aaroncorey&quot;&gt;this one with
Aaron Patterson and Corey Haines&lt;/a&gt; is fun).
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Working-Effectively-Legacy-Michael-Feathers/dp/0131177052&quot;&gt;Working Effectively with Legacy Code&lt;/a&gt;
by Michael Feathers contains many samples of problems in real world code. Of course, 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.discovery.com/tv-shows/mythbusters/&quot;&gt;MythBusters&lt;/a&gt; is a great show, in part, because of the
insights into the discovery process, failures, warts and all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of those various inspirations, I’d like to present to you a beta/pilot
episode of my new endeavor: RealCodez. “Where real world development meets 
real world failure and frustration for your entertainucation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to my son Sam, for editing and additional “contributions”. 
Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/SamSpielberg/videos&quot;&gt;his YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt; for more wackiness. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you love it, hate it, wanna critique it, I’d love to hear your thoughts, 
so shoot me an email at chrismo@clabs.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/192851112&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realcodez.com/2016/11/23/realcodez-pilot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realcodez.com/2016/11/23/realcodez-pilot.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
